IAN CHUA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

0226210388

ianjlchua@gmail.com

https://github.com/ian-jl-chua

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-jl-chua/

TECH EXPOSURE

- HTMI
- CSS
- Tailwind
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React
- Next.Js
- Redux
- SQLite3
- Knex.Js
- Jest

EDUCATION

Certificate in Responsive Web Design freeCodeCamp

Jan 2023 - Sep 2023

Certificate in Applied Software Development

Dev Academy Aotearoa

Jan 2023 - May 2023

Certificate of Carpentry
Unitec

Jun 2013 - Jun 2014

PROFILE

Kia ora, my name is Ian. I recently graduated from Dev Academy (2023) as a Full Stack Web Developer. I am keen to use and grow my newfound skills in developing beautiful, effective, and reliable software.

I have been in the finance industry for 6 years, starting as a Service Consultant, and later as a Banking Consultant at ANZ. These role have allowed me to develop strong communication skills including empathy, conflict resolution and collaboration. My encounters during the pandemic sparked my interest in tech, motivating me to learn how it practically enables industries such as finance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Student - Full Stack Web Development

Dev Academy Aotearoa

Jan 2023 - May 2023

- This is a 15- week intensive Web Development course that covers technical skills needed for a modern Web Development Stack, and soft skills like teamwork, empathy and self-awareness.
- The technical skills covered include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, React, Redux, Knex, SQlite3, TypeScript, Jest. These were applied in various challenges given while Pair Programming during weekdays, and in Friday group projects where we worked collaboratively in small agile teams.
- The course also involved working in various team environments, empathizing with others, and learning how to give and receive growth feedback.
- For our final group project, we worked on a game idea similar to Garticphone, where we implemented all the skills we've learnt from the course.
 As the GitLead for the project, I was responsible for ensuring the commits were merged properly and resolving any conflicts during the merge. I also see the benefits of having a solid plan during the early stages of a project, as this makes delegating workload more efficient.

Banking Consultant

ANZ

Sep 2018 - Present

- Multi-skilled, able to cover the counter when a Service Consultant is away to support the team. Full product knowledge, able to proactively add value to each customer interaction.
- Full knowledge of all systems used in branch including SDA, Systematic, Sales Force and Tableau Dashboard.
- Building good customer relations by providing guidance to the customers on ANZ products like Kiwisaver, Insurance, Personal Loans, Term Deposits and Credit Cards
- KANA delegator during the Covid Lockdown 2020 distributing and managing communication between my colleagues and customers in the Dunedin region.
- Supporting Broker Handover projects during the second Covid Lockdown 2021 as few of my colleagues were unable to set up to work from home.
- Health and Safety Officer for the branch 2022

IAN CHUA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SOFT SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- Teamwork
- · Conflict Resolution
- Collaboration
- Interpersonal Communication
- Active Listening
- Adaptability

ATTRIBUTES

- · Honesty and Integrity
- · Accountable and Responsible
- Quick learner and adapter to new systems and technology
- Management and organization of workflow

REFERENCES

Referee Upon Request

WORK EXPERIENCE

Service Consultant

ANZ

Mar 2017 - Sep 2018

- Assisting customers with over the counter request.
- Cash Passport, Foreign Currency, Bank Cheques, MyTell, CBOS, and CRU
- Guiding customers to the area where their inquiry can be resolved, eg Home Loans to SPB, Personal Loans to BC, Business Banking to PBMs

Copy Center Specialist

Warehouse Stationery

Jun 2015 - Mar 2017

OTHER INTEREST

- · Board games with friends
- Cooking
- Meditation and Yoga
- Cats